In that paulownia wood case was a mummified left paw.
Kanbaru received it from her late mother, and the first time she used it was in fourth grade.
I want to run fast.
Kanbaru had just transferred to a new school after her parents' deaths, but she didn't fit in with her new class
and was often teased for being a slow runner.
She thought that maybe if she got first place at the athletic meet that was going on nearby,
everyone would see her in a different light.
With that in mind, she made her wish.
A monster attacked the four other students who were in the race with Kanbaru.
The next day, all four of them were absent.
Kanbaru soon found Jacobs's "The Monkey's Paw",
and the terrifying contents of the story made her tremble.
Thinking about it normally, in order to cancel the first wish, she'd have to wish on the mummified paw again.
But after researching the mummy, she grew scared,
because she didn't know how the second wish would be granted.
The next day at practice,
it turned out that she would be running with five other students, all different from the last.
So I ran. I poured my heart into getting faster.
It was plain as day that if I didn't do something, something else might happen.
Kanbaru didn't join the track team.
Not knowing how long her wish on the Monkey's Paw would be effective,
she couldn't put herself in a situation where there could be people faster than her.
One day after hearing about my reputation, Senjougahara-senpai came to the gym.
She was the track team's ace, so she came to see me since I had a reputation for being fast.
She challenged me to a 100-meter race, saying it was fine since it was off the record.
Though it was really hard, I had no choice but to turn her down.
She was a wonderful upperclassman.
It wasn't love at first sight, but after talking with her for three days, I started liking her.
I was healed by Senjougahara-senpai.
After that, Kanbaru was able to stop thinking about the mummified paw.
But even still, she would occasionally feel an urge to use it...
When she played against a fierce rival in basketball.
When she had heated arguments with friends.
And...
When I was rejected by Senjougahara-senpai.
In the end, I didn't use it.
It was then that I came to understand that my mother gave me the mummified paw
because she wanted me to become the type of person who could overcome any obstacle with my own strength.
That's why Kanbaru shut up and distanced herself from Senjougahara.
She may have been able to solve Senjougahara's problem by wishing on the paw, but she didn't.
But a year later, Kanbaru found out about me.
She saw me at Senjougahara's side.
Kanbaru no longer knows when she took the paw out of the paulownia wood box.
It never even occurred to her why the paw,
which should have only extended to the wrist, had grown all the way to the elbow.
And before she knew,
Araragi-kun,
young lady...
Now that I understand the whole situation, what's the plan?
The plan?
Come on, Araragi-kun. I'm a pretty good specialist.
I'm more than willing to pretend to be a half-assed authority and help you out of this situation.
W-Will you save me?
I won't save you. I'll only lend you a hand.
The only one who can save you is you yourself, young lady.
But really, Araragi-kun, what am I supposed to do?
Oshino...
I mean, what am I supposed to do to help out this time, Araragi-kun?
First and foremost, there are two simple ways to handle this phenomenon.
One is to let the Rainy Devil kill you, Araragi-kun.
The other is...
to simply cut off that monstrous left arm.
C-Cut it off? Can you just cut off the demon parts?
Will her normal arm grow back afterward?
It's not a lizard's tail, you know.
Nothing's that convenient, wouldn't you agree?
What I'm saying is that an arm is a small price to pay for this.
That's great and all, but it'd be pretty inconvenient for me.
You're trying to kill someone. Isn't that a fair price?
I get what you're trying to say, but hold on, Oshino!
Killing someone isn't what Kanbaru wished for.
Kanbaru just wants to be at Senjougahara's-
"Just wants to be at her side?" Don't make me laugh.
You sure are nice, Araragi-kun.
So nice it makes me sick.
You seriously believe her mushy crap of an excuse, "I just want to be by her side?"
Are you saying... that's not it?
Don't you find it strange, Araragi-kun?
Why do you think it is that when she was in elementary school, her left hand didn't make her faster,
but instead did something like beating up those around her?
Well... doesn't the Monkey's Paw grant wishes in a way that conflicts with the owner's intentions?
But it isn't the Monkey's Paw.
The Rainy Devil is a lesser demon, but a contract is a contract.
If she wished to be faster, normally she would just get faster.
Does beating down her classmates make her faster?
Don't you find that rather strange?
Then why?
Why did a monster in a raincoat come after her classmates?
I'd bet that's because the young lady wanted to beat them up.
She was having a hard time just after her parents died,
and she was being bullied by her classmates,
so it's not very strange for her to have thoughts of revenge.
I...
Of course, I think you were unconscious when you wished for that.
In your own consciousness, you really did wish to be faster.
But that's just the surface; deep inside is different.
Hidden beneath your wish was the dark desire to beat up your classmates.
Though it was unconscious, young lady, I think you should've known very well what really happened.
But you didn't want to admit it, so you went looking for a different explanation for what happened.
That was... the Monkey's Paw!
Blaming the assault of your classmates on the Monkey's Paw distorting your wish,
or claiming that it wasn't what you intended, is just an excuse.
But Oshino...
Are you wondering what real proof I have that lets me say that, Araragi-kun?
Isn't it obvious when you listen to her story?
What happened to that arm of yours when you were in elementary school, young lady?
You didn't realize it until the next day, when you went to class
and only those four seats were empty, isn't that right?
If, at that time, your left arm had ended up like it is now,
you probably would've realized something had happened.
But you didn't include anything of that sort in your story, did you?
Which means that the aberration came one night without you noticing,
latched itself onto your arm, and beat up your classmates, fulfilling your wish.
And without you noticing, the aberration separated from your arm and left.
It probably grew from a hand to an arm
using a portion of your soul that was taken in exchange for granting your wish.
Hey, Oshino, that means...
Believing the attacker's excuse, you really are a nice person, Araragi-kun.
It's not surprising that she'd be jealous enough
to want to kill the guy who took away her beloved senpai.
When she attacked you, it wasn't against her intentions.
She intended to attack you.
It's about time.
I've been waiting.
Took you longer than expected.
Yeah, I don't really know how much is too much...
It might not even be enough.
But this way's better than having her take too much.
Both for me... and for Shinobu.
Since you're about to have a big fight with a demon, Araragi-kun,
I'd say it's not the best time to be thinking too much like that.
You're really close to your limit, but I still don't think you have a good chance of winning.
Even if your opponent is only going to use her left arm.
A contract, huh?
It's fine as long as the demon just goes back to the spirit world afterward.
It'll be fine. I can at least guarantee that much.
If the contract can't be fulfilled, then it becomes void, got it?
It also becomes void if the demon can't grant the young lady's wish.
So basically, if I'm not killed by the devil, huh?
Exactly.
Of course, even if you power up by giving Shinobu-chan as much of your blood as you can,
Compared to during spring break when you were still a vampire,
I don't think you can draw forth more than a tenth of the power you did then.
That's quite the number.
Even so, you can't just borrow Shinobu-chan.
If you do, it'll be more than just a bluff... We really will have to chop off the young lady's arm.
Exterminating it means something because you're doing it.
I'll keep an eye on your bag and valuables, Araragi-kun.
It'll be hard to move if you're carrying them, won't it?
Thanks.
Okay, hold on a second.
Could you tell me one thing, Araragi-kun?
What is it?
Why do you want to save someone who tried to kill you?
Even if it was unconsciously, that young lady chose you as her hated rival in love.
When you realized it was her in the raincoat, why did you decide to talk to her about it?
You should've ignored her and come straight to me when that happened.
Everyone hates someone at some point.
I think I'll pass on getting killed.
If looking up to Senjougahara is the reason Kanbaru hates me, I can forgive that.
I see. Well, if that's what you've decided, then so be it.
I don't care. It's none of my business.
Now then, Araragi-kun.
Go help the young lady out.
Just so you know, once you go in, you can't come out until it's over.
The door won't open from the inside, no matter what.
And of course, if anything does happen, neither I nor Shinobu-chan will come to save you.
Don't forget that.
Right.
Sorry for the trouble.
No worries.
Hi.
Sorry, Kanbaru!
Is it working?
She can use not only her left arm, but her legs too?!
Not only does the Rainy Devil left arm want to attack me, but Kanbaru herself, too.
Unconsciously, Kanbaru is rejecting it.
She's rejecting that her wish won't come true.
That I won't be killed.
Kanbaru has no intention of giving up on Senjougahara.
Please, cut it off.
I don't need this left arm...
What the hell are you talking about?
There's no way we can do that.
What about basketball?!
I tried to kill a person!
It's a small price to pay in comparison.
Come on, Kanbaru. I'm telling you, I don't care about that.
If you're going to cut it off, I know a good way to do it.
If you use Shinobu-chan's blade, it's possible to cut off that arm so fast you won't even feel it.
Even with Shinobu-chan in her current state, cutting off a thin arm like that is a piece of cake.
Shut your mouth, Oshino!
Hey, Kanbaru!
It's not something to worry so much about, is it?
There's no reason for you to feel responsible at all.
The Monkey's Paw... no, this aberration called the Rainy Devil is what did this.
The aberration only granted her wish, didn't it?
She made the wish, and it granted it.
Wasn't it the same with Tsundere-chan?
I don't care, Araragi-senpai.
You have to care! There's no way you can't!
What are you saying?!
And what are you going to do about Senjougahara?
I... want you and Senjougahara to...
That's enough.
I don't care anymore, not even about Senjougahara-senpai.
I don't care.
I give up, so...
You can't.
Kanbaru Suruga!
HATE! HATE! HATE! HATE!
Looks like you've been enjoying yourself.
Having fun without me, are you?
How thoughtless, Araragi-kun.
S-Senjougahara....
Did Oshino use my phone?
Araragi-kun, you lied to me.
You tricked me by saying you hit a telephone pole, and you hid everything about Kanbaru.
Didn't we promise not to do that when we started going out?
Not to keep secrets like that from each other, no matter how small?
No, I...
I'll kill you 10,000 times over.
But really, Araragi-kun, it looks like you've already died 10,000 times or so...
Maybe I'll forgive you just this once.
You weren't really stupid enough to think that if you died,
the entire problem would be solved, were you, Araragi-kun?
Give me a break.
If you died, I'd obviously do everything in my power to kill Kanbaru.
Araragi-kun, are you trying to turn me into a murderer?
She saw right through it.
Really, she's so understanding...
What really disgusts me most, though, is that even if you didn't have that body,
I know you would have thrown yourself at this problem in just the same way.
If you did these stupid things simply because you knew you could rely on your immortal body,
I would just tell you to do as you please.
But Araragi-kun, the way you just jump into these things like it's the obvious response... I just don't get it.
Well, be it a terrible burden, an unncecessary intrusion, an unasked favor,
it might not be too bad if it's you who's doing it, Araragi-kun.
Let's say that one plan was to defeat the demon and make it impossible for the hidden part
of Kanbaru's wish to be fulfilled...
but revealing to Senjougahara that Kanbaru really wanted to kill me, making it impossible
for the other side of her wish to be fulfilled was another plan, as well.
What's more, Senjougahara swore right in front of the demon that she'd kill Kanbaru if Kanbaru killed me.
It couldn't get away with feigning ignorance.
To the Rainy Devil, the decision had already been made.
I can't believe you saw through all that, Oshino.
You... even when compared to a demon, are one magnificent bastard.
Long time no see, Kanbaru.
I'm glad you're well.
I love you, Senjougahara-senpai.
I know.
I don't really love you.
Will you stay by my side despite that?
Sorry I kept you waiting.
Man, even being the fall guy has its good points.
It was like I had a comic role written just for me.
Even though I of all people should've known how greedy and what a sore loser Senjougahara Hitagi is.
If it really was so important, there's no way she'd give up on it.
Butting in.
Being nosy.
Doing unwelcome favors.
But, well...
How should I put it?
Both of them are really hard to deal with.
Nii-chan! Come on, it's morning!
You gotta get up already!
Come on!
Mornin', Araragi-senpai.
Good morning, Kanbaru-san.
Do you need something?
Senjougahara-senpai called this morning and asked me to come meet you.
Let me grab your bag.
All right, let's go, Senpai!
Hey, what about your club?
Don't you have practice on Sundays?
The break before exams is coming, so you have to get serious.
No, I can't play basketball anymore.
It may be a bit early, but I'm quitting. It's really only half-done, after all.
The demon left, but in the end my arm didn't go back to normal.
There's really no way I can keep playing basketball with my arm like it is.
But in any case, it is pretty powerful and easy to use.
Give my bag back, now.
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
On the subject of Koyomi, he's more than just our brother.
Bro, you mean?
Do you know about Sanninbou?
Sanninbou?
It's a certain date on which some believe building a house will cause a great fire,
destroying three neighboring houses!
What a frightening belief!
As expected of the brother of the fire sisters!
Just as expected of our brother!
But check this out, it's a textbook method to get away with murder!
What kind of recipe?
The criminal is one who uses Sanninbou!
A license to kill!
With - or without - a reason!
Postview quiz!
Postview?!
Last time Suruga Monkey Part Two!
Everyone knows!
Next time! Nadeko Snake, Part One!
That's Sen-chan's turn.
Don't push it.